

Martin Friedrich (He/Him)

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR & DEVOPS ENGINEER

Details

Forstenrieder Allee 27 Munich, 81476 Germany +49 1515 465 4844 npanic@br0.space

NATIONALITY

German

11.09.1988

Links

Portofolio / Aboutme

PGP / Keybase

<u>Linkedin</u>

Github

Skills

Adaptability

Collaboration & Teamwork

Critical thinking

Active Learning

Good Communication

Problem Solving

Languages

English

German

About me

I'm a SysOps/DevOps Engineer with 5+ years of hands-on experience supporting, automating and optimising mission-critical deployments on-premise and in the Cloud.

Config Management and Device Management are my passion.

Led a team of 6 at Zeuz GmbH that created a bare-metal orchestrator for Kubernetes based Gameserver workloads.

Employment History

Senior System Administrator / Client Platform Engineer, Improbable Ltd, Remote

OCTOBER 2021 - AUGUST 2022

- CI/CD support for internal Customers
- Code Security Scanning (SonarQube, Whitesource, Renovate)
- Continuous Delivery on Kubernetes (Gitlab-CI, Buildkite, Github Actions)
- Infrastructure Configuration Management (Ansible, Puppet, Terraform)
- Migration of CI pipelines from Gitlab-CI to Buildkite
- Mobile Device management (Micromdm, AzureAD, Puppet)
- Monitoring & Alerting (Prometheus stack, ELK stack, Thanos)
- On-premise MacOS Build infrastructure (Anka)
- Package Management (AutoPKG, Intune, Debian apt)
- Platform Administration (Google Workspace, Atlassian, Slack, Office365)

Senior System Administrator / Teamlead, Improbable Ltd, Remote

FEBRUARY 2020 - NOVEMBER 2020

- Cluster administration (Docker Swarm, Kubernetes)
- Configuration Management (Ansible, Packer, Terraform)
- · Continuous Delivery on Kubernetes (Gitlab-Cl, Buildkite)
- Database Administration (Elasticsearch, Redis Cluster, Postgre)
- Mentoring a trainee
- Monitoring & Alerting (Prometheus, Victoria-metrics, ELK, Thanos)

Senior System Administrator / Teamlead, Zeuz GmbH, Munich

JANUARY 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020

- Building a Docker based gameserver Platform
- Cluster administration (Docker Swarm, Kubernetes)
- Configuration Management (Ansible, Terraform, Packer)
- Continuous Delivery on Kubernetes (Gitlab-Cl, Buildkite)
- Continuous Security (Gitlab SAST/DAST)
- Database Administration (Elasticsearch, Redis Cluster, Postgre)
- Managing bare-metal infrastructure (Ansible)
- Mentoring a trainee
- Monitoring & Alerting (Prometheus, Victoria-metrics, ELK, Thanos)

Senior System Administrator / DevOps Engineer, Daypaio GmbH, Munich

JUNE 2018 - JANUARY 2019

- Configuration Management (Ansible)
- Continuous Security (Gitlab SAST/DAST)
- Continuous Delivery of NodeJS Applications (Gitlab-CI)
- Database Administration (MongoDB, Redis Cluster)
- Migration of CI/CD pipelines from Bamboo, Jenkins to Gitlab-CI
- Monitoring & Alerting (Prometheus stack)
- Platform Administration (Google Workspace, Atlassian, Slack)

Hobbies

3D fractals Generative Art Multiplayer Games

System Administrator / Teamlead Infrastructure, Draglet GmbH, Munich

OCTOBER 2017 - MAY 2018

- Administration of Crypto Assets
- Configuration Management (Ansible)
- Continuous Delivery of Java Applications (Gitlab-CI)
- Database Administration (MariaDB)
- Firewall & VPN Administration (opnSense, OpenVPN, strongswan)
- Migration of CI pipelines from Jenkins to Gitlab-CI
- Monitoring & Alerting (Icinga, Prometheus)
- Platform Administration (Google Workspace, Atlassian, Slack)
- Recruiting team members

System Administrator, Hörer und Flamme GmbH, Munich

OCTOBER 2015 - OCTOBER 2017

- Configuration Management (Ansible)
- Continuous Delivery of PHP Applications (Gitlab-CI)
- Data imports for Marketing Campaigns
- Device management
- Directory Administration (ActiveDirectory, AzureAD, LDAP, Univention Corporate Server)
- Firewall & VPN Administration (pfSense, OpenVPN, strongswan)
- Mentoring a trainee
- Monitoring & Alerting (Nagios, check_mk)
- PBX Administration (Asterisk, Pascom MobyDick)
- Running On-premise Infrastructure (Proxmox, FreeNAS)

Education

Qualifying secondary school certificate, Ridlerschule, Munich

NOVEMBER 2000 - JULY 2005

Klenze Gymnasium, Munich

NOVEMBER 1999 - JULY 2000

Projects

Aboutme website

https://github.com/networkpanic/npanic.br0.space

Home-Infra: Kubernetes running at home.

https://github.com/networkpanic/home-infra

Archlinux Package for Mandelbulber2 (with opencl support)

https://aur.archlinux.org/packages/mandelbulber2-opencl-git